MAHINDRA BHAGAT

Angular Developer | Agile Methodologies | Front-End Expertise



mahindra.bhagat2306@gmail.com



Pune, Maharashtra

SUMMARY

Dedicated **Angular Developer** with around **3.8 years'** experience in front-end development, expert in Angular and Agile lifecycle with a proven record of delivering robust web applications. Excited to apply advanced technical skills and extensive knowledge in web services to contribute effectively to mission-critical programs.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

11/2024 - Present

SISL Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

DELHI

- Developed and maintained a Government of India web application using Angular 12 and Bootstrap.
- Contributed to the development of a microservices-based architecture, ensuring scalability and modularity.
- Designed and implemented a basic API to support project requirements, facilitating smooth front-end and back-end integration.
- Worked closely with back-end developers to integrate RESTful APIs, enhancing system

Front-End Developer

08/2022 - 11/2024

Taashee Linux Services Pvt. Ltd.

DELHI

- Developed and maintained **Government of India** web application using Angular 12.
- Led to the development of angular **Micro-services-based** architecture.
- Worked closely with UX teams to design applications with user-friendly features.
- Coordinated with back-end developers to integrate RESTful APIs, improving the scalability of the client's digital infrastructure.
- Championed the Agile SCRUM methodology, reducing the product's time with maintaining high code quality.

Front-End Developer

07/2021 - 08/2022

CI Solutions

Mumbai, Maharashtra.

- Developed and maintained scalable web applications using **Angular 10** & **PrimeNG**, with a focus on performance optimization across multiple projects.
- Work On **Key Cloak** Integration on Intranet System.
- Enhanced code maintainability by implementing efficient Github branching strategies.
- Contributed to the development of a micro services-based architecture.
- Prepared comprehensive documentation, including user manuals and technical guides.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Savitribai Phule Pune University

06/2016 - 07/2019

Sinhgad Institute Of Technology, Lonavala

Diploma In Engineering

Maharashtra State Board Of Technical Education

06/2013 - 06/2016

Government Polytechnic, Yavatmal



PROJECTS

Fancy Project

Client: National Informatic Center

Description:

It is an Online Bidding System for Vehicle Number Plates in collaboration with the esteemed client, National Informatics Centre (NIC)

Responsibilities:

- Designing and developing userfriendly web-based platform by using Angular 12
- Integrating the online bidding system with the existing infrastructure of RTO to facilate seamless communication
- Collaborating with NIC team to provide to provide training and support to RTO and State Admin

Auto Billing

Client: Tata Motors Ltd

Description:

The Intranet Auto Billing System It is an Facilates and effective communication Between Tata motors dealers, Plant Logistic manager and Central Business Team where dealer could request various Type of Purchase Order

Responsibilities:

- Customized Designed and **Developed Interfaces for Dealers** PLM and CBT ensuring that it should have efficient UX
- Prepared an comprehensive documentation, including user manuals and technical guide
- Integrate an Key cloak User Authentication.

SKILL SETS

Languages	HTML5, JavaScript, Typescript, CSS3
IDE	Visual Studio Code.
Tools	Jira
Frameworks	Angular 10, Angular 12, Bootstrap 5, Prime NG, Angular Material
Versioning	Git